A Finding Aid to the Jacqueline Gourevitch Papers, 1949-2019, bulk 1955-2005, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Jacqueline Gourevitch papers
1949-2019
bulk 1955-2005
Archives of American Art
Gourevitch, Jacqueline
AAA.gourjacq
Archival Resource Key
5.6 Linear feet
The papers of painter and educator Jacqueline Gourevitch measure 5.6 linear feet and date from 1946-2019 and document her education at Black Mountain College, Black Mountain, N.C., and the Art Students League; her teaching career; and exhibitions in Chicago and New York through biographical material, teaching files, personal and professional correspondence, gallery and exhibition files, and printed material.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1949-2017 (0.15 linear feet, Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1949-2017 (1.05 linear feet, Box 2-3)
Series 3: Professional Files, 1949-2019 (0.95 linear feet, Box 3-4)
Series 4: Gallery and Exhibition Files, circa 1950-2012 (2.45 linear feet, Box 3-5)
Series 5: Teaching Files, 1960-2015 (0.8 linear feet, Box 5-6)
Series 6: Printed Materials, 1958-1997 (0.2 linear feet, Box 6)
Biographical / Historical
Jacqueline Gourevitch (1933- ) is a painter and educator in New York, New York. Gourevitch was born in Paris and moved to New York with her parents when she was a child. There she attended the High School of Music and Art where she decided to pursue a career as a painter. In 1950, she attended a summer program for art studies at Black Mountain College. She studied Art History at the University of Chicago and took courses at the Art Institute of Chicago and the Art Students League. In 1954, she married Victor Gourevitch, a graduate student at the University of Chicago, and they had two sons.
Although Gourevitch is most widely known for her Cloud paintings, her work focuses on the sky and clouds and incorporates the earth and the city, often observed from a distance or a high place. After many years of painting independently, Gourevitch began teaching in the early 1970s. She taught courses in drawing and painting at Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut, and Cooper Union in New York. She held several Visiting Artist positions throughout her life and her work has been exhibited and included in permanent collections across the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated in 2019 by Jacqueline Gourevitch.
Scope and Contents
The papers of painter and educator Jacqueline Gourevitch measure 5.6 linear feet and date from 1946-2019 and document her education at Black Mountain College, Black Mountain, N.C., and the Art Students League; her teaching career; and exhibitions in Chicago and New York through biographical material, teaching files, personal and professional correspondence, gallery and exhibition files, and printed material.
Materials in this collection document Gourevitch's career as an artist and educator. Her early interest in pursuing a career as a painter is highlighted through biographical materials that include correspondence, alumni lists, and notes from Black Mountain College and the High School of Music and Arts related to class reunions; a 1954 Fulbright application; and teacher bios from the Art Students League and Chicago Arts Institute.
Although her work as an artist and as an educator often overlapped, Gourevitch did not begin teaching until the 1970s. The years she spent painting are documented through exhibition announcements and clippings; gallery and exhibition files that include correspondence with curators and gallery owners, loan agreements, price lists, checklists, photographs and notes; various projects she worked on, including the Black Mountain College Project and numerous exhibitions related to Black Mountain College; and through correspondence with colleagues, other artists, including Ellen Lanyon, and friends. Gourevitch's teaching files document her career as an instructor and visiting artist through correspondence with students, faculty and staff at various institutions; lectures, lecture notes, and lecture announcements; course descriptions; class lists; syllabi; campus maps; and letters of recommendation. Evidence of her lasting impact on her students can be found throughout the collection through correspondence, clippings, and exhibition announcements.
Educators -- New York (State) -- New York; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Women artists; Interviews
- Biographical Material, 1949-2017; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.15 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical material document Gourevitch's education and her interest in painting. Materials include a pamphlet from Camp Strawderman; teacher bios from her attendance at the Art Students League in 1952 and the Art Institute of Chicago in 1956, including Charles Alston and Paul Wieghart; a Fulbright scholarship application to study in France, which she "reluctantly turned down"; and alumni lists, classmate bios, and correspondence from Black Mountain College and the High School of Music and Art reunions.
  - Black Mountain College Classmates, circa 1995-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Black Mountain College Reunion, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - BMC Personal, 1950-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Camp Strawderman, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fulbright, Scholarship Application, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - My Teachers, Art Students League in 1952 and the Art Institute of Chicago in 1956, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Music and Art 1947-51 [High School Reunion], 2001, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1949-2017; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.05 Linear feet Box 2-3
  Correspondence documents Gourevitch's career as an artist and educator, and her personal connections to friends and other artists she met while studying at Black Mountain College and in Chicago, including Marion Miller and Ellen Lanyon. She often received photographs, clippings, and exhibition announcements, and corresponded frequently with current and former students.
  - Artists' Evenings, Connecticut Group, 1992-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - D'Ambrosio, Mirella, 1949-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ellen Lanyon, b.1926-d.2013, 1986, 2013-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Former Students, 1986-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Former Students and Letters of Recommendation, 2008-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Friends, 1949-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
  - Frizzell, Deborah, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Goodman, Ann, 1953-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Kranse, Lucille, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miller, Bonnie (Marion Miller), 1985-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Phibbs, Gwen and Phil, 1978-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reed, Arden, 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Rosoff, Patricia, Re "Innocent Eye: A Passionate Look at Contemporary Art", 2012-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Staller, Luba, 1951-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - Staller, Luba (in Iran), 1971-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Stokes - Lucier (Wendy Stokes and Amanda Lucier), 1994-1996, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Student Correspondence, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Students, A-C, 1970-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Students, E-J, 1979-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Students, K-M, 1971-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Students, N-S, 1975-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Students, T-Z, 1975-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan Students, 2013-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Professional Files, 1949-2019; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.95 Linear feet Box 3-4
  Professional Files document projects that Gourevitch was involved in outside of teaching and exhibiting her work. Although art related, the material document her passion for art education and her strong ties with the art world and to Black Mountain College. She participated in numerous projects related to Black Mountain College, including the Black Mountain College Project dedicated to documenting the history and influence of the college's unique educational experiment; costume work for Susan Foster's "Corpus Delecti" choreography; contributions to art related publications and films; and her work with the Ora Lerman Charitable Trust, Women in the Arts, and the Connecticut Commission on the Arts. Materials include transcripts, correspondence, pamphlets, lists, clippings, notes, and photocopies from the North Carolina State Archives.
  - Archive BMC Photos, Donation to N.C. State Archives, 1972, 2008-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Art New England, Louis Tarlow, 1980-1990, 2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Art Now: New York, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Avenues to the Arts (World Politics) Correspondence and Final Manuscript, 1958-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Black Mountain College Museum and Arts Center, 1998-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Black Mountain College Museum Arts Center Artist Talk, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Black Mountain College Research Project Transcript Correspondence, 1971-1974, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Black Mountain College Project Interview Transcript Final, 1998-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - BMCMA Videos, Black Mountain College Museum and Arts Center Oral History Project, 2014-2019; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (DVD) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - BMC Bard Show,The Arts at Black Mountain College, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - BMC Miscellaneous Shows at International Galleries, 2005-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - City Art Collection, City of Middletown, 1982-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Classroom Facility, Western Connecticut State University, 1982-1985, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut, 1976-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Costume work for Susan Foster's "Corpus Delecti" Choreography, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - ICA Show: Helen Molesworth, "Leap Before You Look: Black Mountain College, 1933-1957", 2014-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Imitation: Notes - Quotes for "Avenues to the Arts", 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Janice, BMC, Panel Discussion at Film Screening of "Fully Awake: Black Mountain College", 2016-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Juries, Boston, 1981-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Loretta Howard Gallery BMC Show, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Mary Emma Harris, Black Mountain College Project, 1970-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - NC Archive JHE file 2017, photocopied Black Mountain College student file, 1949-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Ora Lerman Charitable Trust, 1986-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Paul Goodman Film by Jonathan Lee, 1972, 2006-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Visiting Artist: Art Institute of Chicago, 1975-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Visual Arts Slide Bank/Connecticut Commission on the Arts, 1984-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Women in the Arts, circa 1972-circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Gallery and Exhibition Files, circa 1950-2012; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.45 Linear feet Box 3-5
  Gallery and Exhibition Files document Gourevitch's participation in group and solo exhibitions at galleries and museums across the United States, primarily in Chicago and New York, and span six decades. They also document museums and galleries that acquired her work either by donation or purchase. Notable institutions include DFN Gallery, Eleanor Rigelhaupt Gallery, Paesaggio Gallery, Tibor de Nagy Gallery, Whitney Museum of American Art, Wadsworth Atheneum, Yale University Art Gallery, Art Institute of Chicago, and Black Mountain College Museum and Arts Center. Materials in this series include correspondence, checklists, price lists, exhibition announcements, floor plans, photographs, rights and reproduction requests, catalog mock-ups, and photocopied guest books.
  - 414 Art Workshop and Gallery, "Jacqueline Gourevitch: City and Still Life Paintings" (1957), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Aerial Perspectives: Imagination, Reality and Abstraction" (1997), 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Art Rental and Sales Gallery of the Art Institute of Chicago, 1956-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Borden, Jack; For Spacious Skies, 1983-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Charles River Art Center, circa 1964-circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Collection, 1970-1995, 2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Cloudworks" (1982), 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Condeso/Lawler Gallery, 1979-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Contemporary Landscape Painting and Drawing" (1998), 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - DFN Gallery Current, 1998-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - DFN Gallery 2000, "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Paintings" (2000), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - DFN Gallery "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Above and Below" (2002), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - DFN Gallery Group Exhibitions, 1998-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Eleanor Rigelhaupt Gallery, 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - "Eleven by Eleven by Eleven for Puffin" (1999), 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Emily Sorkin, Inc., 1982-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Exhibition Momentum" (1956, 1957), 1956-1957, 2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Forces of Nature: Fire, Water, Earth and Air" (2000), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Fischbach Gallery, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Group Shows, 1957-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Group Shows, Chicago and Pennsylvania, circa 1950-circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Aerial Notations: Paintings and Drawings" (1994), 1986-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Aerial Notations: Paintings and Drawings" (1994), catalog, 1991-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Aerial Notations: Paintings and Drawings" (1994), letters, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Clouds" (2008), catalog, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Tamarind Lithographs" (1974), 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Jacqueline Gourevitch: Paintings and Drawings" (1983), 1982-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - LaMotta Fine Arts/Paesaggio Gallery, 2000-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mailing Lists, 2002-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mailing Lists: Addresses and Business Cards, circa 2000-circa 2019; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Mary Ryan Gallery, 2005-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Matrix: A Changing Exhibition of Contemporary Art" (1975), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Matrix is 20!" (1995), 1979-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "My Friends - Their Vision" (2006), 2005-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Paesaggio Gallery #1, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Paesaggio Gallery #2, 1994-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Paesaggio Gallery '96, 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Paesaggio Gallery '99, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Paesaggio Gallery, Agreement and Inventory, 1993-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Paesaggio Gallery Current, 1998-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Paesaggio Gallery Others, 1991-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Paesaggio Gallery, Reviews, 1994-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - R2 Gallery (R squared), 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Recent Paintings: Jacqueline Gourevitch" (1987), 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Resonance" (1992), 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Roko Gallery, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Shows Closed, Various Exhibitions, '77-'78, 1977-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Skying" (1972), 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Stephen Rosenberg Gallery, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Tamarind Lithographs, 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "The Connecticut Biennial" (1989), 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Connecticut Gallery, 1986-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "To Enchant (blue)" (1994), 1988-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Gallery of Contemporary Art at Sacred Heart University, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Painting Center, 1995-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The William Benton Museum of Art, 1994-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery, 1970-1978, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
  - Various Group Exhibitions, 1967-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10-13)
  - Various Exhibitions, Solo and Chicago, 1982-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Various Shows, Chicago, 1957-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Walkey Gallery, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Watercolor" (2002), Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Whitney Museum Biennial (1973), 1967-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Yeshiva University, "Jacqueline Gourevitch: The Walls of Jerusalem" (1983), 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Teaching Files, 1960-2015; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 5-6
  Teaching files document Gourevitch's career as an educator, including art instructor and visiting artist positions at numerous institutions across the United States including Wellesley College, Cooper Union, University of Huston, Vassar College, University of New Mexico (Albuquerque); University of California (Berkeley), and others. She taught beginning and advanced painting and drawing, and has given numerous talks and lectures on a variety of topics including specific artists and styles. Materials include notes, lesson plans, handouts, syllabi, lecture notes and announcements, grant paperwork, correspondence, campus maps, committee notes, and pamphlets.
  - Advanced Practice, 1984-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Basic Drawing, Cooper Union, 1989-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Berkeley, 1974-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - CAA '84 Talk on Contemporary Landscape, 1984-circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Cooper Union, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Donald Kuspit notes, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Drawing I and II, 1970-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Handouts, circa 1986-circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Hartford Art School, 1973-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Integrated Painting and Drawing, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Kandinsky lecture at Mount Holyoke, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Know Your Museum: Modern Painting Lectures, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
  - Lecture Announcements, 1975-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Lecture Research on Ruins, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Michael Fried notes for Advanced Painting lecture, 9/12/73, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Mount Hoyle, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Models, 1977, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Notes, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Susan Rothenberg talk with John Paoletti, 1984, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Painting I and II, 1968-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Readings, circa 1965-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Side Talks, 1982-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Tamarind Institute, University of New Mexico, 1972-1973, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Teaching: Class Lists and Descriptions, 1964-1967, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1974-1975, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - University of Houston, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - University of Houston and Yale Committee on Art, George Bunker, 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, 1973-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Various Jobs, 1978-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Vassar College, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Visiting Artist Lectures, Wadsworth Atheneum, 1996-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Visual Arts Forum, 1984-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1966-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Yale Committee on Art, 1975-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Printed Material, 1958-1997; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 6
  Printed Material document Gourevitch's painting career and the work of her former students. Materials include clippings reviewing her work; exhibition announcements, notes, and letters from her former students; and various exhibition announcements and clippings related to her shows.
  - Clippings, Art in New England, 1980, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, Arts Magazine, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, Connecticut Magazine, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Former Students, Exhibition Announcements, Notes, and Letters, 1974-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22-24)
  - Various Exhibition Announcements and Clippings, 1958-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)